https://www.lapua.com/about-us/our-privacy-policy/

Part of Nammo group
About us | Finest Ammunition | Cases | Bullets – Privacy Policy
Nammo Lapua Privacy Policy
Version:  17.6.2020
Nammo Lapua Oy (“Nammo Lapua”; “we”; “us”; “our”) takes your privacy very seriously and is committed to protecting your personal information. This privacy policy sets out the way in which any personal information you provide to us is used and kept secure by Nammo Lapua. It applies whenever we collect your personal data including when you use our website or other digital platforms, so please read it carefully.
Point of contact
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or about your personal data, please email us at dpo.lapua(a)nammo.com or dpo.lapuaclub(a)nammo.com (if related to the Lapua Club profile) or write to us at the following address:
Data Protection Officer
Nammo Lapua Oy
PL 5
62101 Lapua, Finland
1. About our privacy policy
This privacy policy explains what information we may collect about you, how we may use it, and the steps we take to ensure that it is kept secure. We also explain your rights in respect of your personal data.
2. Collection and use of personal data
All personal information that we collect about you will be recorded, used, and protected by us in accordance with applicable data protection legislation and this privacy policy. We may supplement the information that you provide with other information that we obtain from our interactions with you or which we receive from other organizations, for example our digital services partners. Our current digital services partners are Staart Oy, j2 Global Canada, Inc., Rightspot Oy and Package Media Oy.
This privacy policy refers to how we administer information that you may provide to us on or via:
1.1. Website www.lapua.com
1.2. Contact form on www.lapua.com
1.3. Lapua Newsletter
1.4. Our mobile app Lapua Ballistics
1.5. the Lapua Club web site at www.club.lapua.com
1.6. Our brand or company pages on various social media platforms.
Please note that our website and other digital platforms may contain links to third party websites and/or digital platforms. We are only responsible for the privacy practices and security of our own digital platforms. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies and procedures of each and every other website / digital platform that you visit.
Where a password is required to access certain areas of our digital platforms, you are responsible for keeping your password secure and confidential. Please do not share or disclose your password to any other person.
General description of purposes of the processing of personal data
We process your personal data for the following purposes:
to enable us to administer any competitions or other offers/promotions you enter into
to personalize and improve your experience on our digital platforms
to track your activity on our digital platforms
to personalize and/or tailor any communications that we may send you
to personalize and/or tailor any marketing communications that you may consent to receiving  from us for record keeping purposes
to carry out market research so that we can improve the products and services we offer
When you register to receive marketing communications from us, enter one of our competitions, fill in one of our forms (whether online or offline) register a profile on our app Lapua Ballistics, or otherwise expressly provide us with your personal information, we may collect and store any personal information that you provide to us and may use it to personalize and improve your experience on our digital platforms, provide products and services you request from us, and carry out profiling and market research.
When you interact with our digital platforms, we may also automatically collect the following information about your visit:
how you have reached our digital platform and the internet protocol (IP) address you have used
your browser type, versions and plug-ins, and your operating system
your journey through our digital platform, including which links you click on and any searches you made, how long you stayed on a page, and other page interaction information
which videos you have watched and for how long
what content you like or share
which adverts you saw and responded to
your subscription status
information collected in any forms you complete
We may also infer your country of location from the IP address you have used to access our digital platforms and we may analyze which marketing activity led to your taking specific action on our digital platforms (e.g. downloading / registering to the Lapua Ballistics app).
Below you can find more detailed information concerning our personal data processing activities.
1.1. Website www.lapua.com
We collect personal data related to visitors on our website www.lapua.com through Google Analytics for analyzing visitor behavior on our website. The personal data collected consists of visitor’s IP address, country of location based on visitor’s IP address, and the website domain visited. When visiting our website, you are asked to give your consent to the processing of your personal data.
To learn more about privacy policies of Google, please visit https://policies.google.com/privacy.
Personal data is also processed by Staart Oy.
1.2. Contact form on www.lapua.com
The information given by you through our contact form are processed for the purpose of contacting you. By sending us a message through our contact form, you have given your consent to the processing of your personal data.
The personal data collected through our contact form consists of your email address and the message sent by you through the contact form. You are required to provide your email address and the message, otherwise we are not able to contact you. Other personal data collected through our contact form consist of your first and last name, postal address and phone number. You are not required to provide such personal data to us.
1.3. Lapua Newsletter
Based on your consent for subscribing our Lapua Newsletter, we may send you electronic marketing communication related to our products and services. In order to subscribe for our Lapua Newsletter, you are required to provide your first name, last name, email address and country.
We want you to be the first to know about new products, competitions, Lapua Team members, match news and others.
We use Campaigner by j2 Global Canada, Inc. as our newsletter service provider.
1.4. Our mobile app Lapua Ballistics
Subject to your consent for providing your personal data when creating a user profile to our mobile app Lapua Ballistics, we process your name, email address and country. Based on your consent, we may also send you electronic marketing communication related to our products and services. Furthermore, we analyze the use of the mobile app on country-level. The mobile app is technically provided by RightSpot Oy.
1.5. the Lapua Club web site at www.club.lapua.com
Subject to your consent for providing your personal data when creating a user profile to our Lapua Club service, we process your user name, name, e-mail address and postal address. You can also provide your phone number. Contact details are used for sending our promotional materials to you. Based on your consent, we may also send you electronic marketing communication related to our products and services.
You can register our products by scanning a QR code on our product package in the Lapua Club service. Subject to your consent, we may process location of the product based on IP address used for your registration. The web site platform is provided by Package Media Oy.
1.6. Our brand or company pages on various social media platforms.
We are also present on various social medial platforms, such as Facebook, Instagram, YouTube and Twitter. The personal data collected by us through social media platforms are used for analytics purposes. If you have participated in raffle organized by us on social media platform, we collect your name and phone number as well as postal address through private message if you win in a raffle for the purpose of sending you a prize. The personal data collected by us through social media platform raffles are deleted from our files within one (1) month after the raffle.
Please note that our website and other digital platforms may contain links to third party websites and/or digital platforms. We are only responsible for the privacy practices and security of our own digital platforms. We recommend that you check the privacy and security policies and procedures of each and every other website / digital platform that you visit.
Where a password is required to access certain areas of our digital platforms, you are responsible for keeping your password secure and confidential. Please do not share or disclose your password to any other person.
Cookies and other tools
We use cookies and other similar online technologies, such as your browser’s local data storage, to collect data from your device. Cookies are small text files that your browser saves in your device. Cookies often contain an anonymous individual identifier, which we can use to measure how many different browsers are visiting our website, and how our online services are being used.
You can prevent the use of cookies by changing your browser settings. Preventing cookies may have an impact as to how our services and website function.
3. Disclosure of your information
Any and all information you provide us is treated as confidential. All information is stored securely and is accessed by authorized personnel only. Nammo Lapua implements and maintains appropriate technical, security and organizational measures to protect Personal Data against unauthorized or unlawful processing and use, and against accidental loss, destruction, damage, theft or disclosure.
Recipients of personal data
In order to provide promotional materials and services to you, we may need to appoint other organizations to carry out some of the data processing activities on our behalf. These may include, for example, mobile app developers, website administrators, QR code analytics providers, and mailing and delivery organizations. Our current digital services partners are Staart Oy, j2 Global Canada, Inc., Rightspot Oy and Package Media Oy.
We may share your data with social media platforms for the purposes of selecting and serving relevant adverts to you via those platforms, and to search engine and analytics providers.
We may share your data with third parties 1) if we are under a legal or regulatory duty to do so; 2) to lawfully assist the police or security services with the prevention and detection of crime or terrorist activity; 3) where such disclosure is necessary to protect the safety or security of any persons; 4) and/or otherwise as permitted under applicable law.
4. Data transfers to countries outside the European Union or the European Economic Area
All processing of personal data is performed in accordance with privacy rights and regulations of the EU Regulations (EU) 2016/679 known as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and Nammo Lapua’s processing will take place in accordance with the GDPR. Some of the organizations to which we may disclose your personal information are situated outside of the European Union or the European Economic Area in countries which may not have laws that protect privacy rights as extensively as in the European Union. If we do transfer your personal information to other territories, we will take proper steps to ensure that your information is protected in accordance with this privacy policy.
In all instances where we disclose your information to third parties, we will ensure that your information is appropriately protected.
5. Retention and deletion
You may correct or update your personal information at any time by contacting our above address, emailing us at dpo.lapua(a)nammo.com or dpo.lapuaclub(a)nammo.com (if related to the Lapua Club profile) or by changing your profile in the Lapua Ballistics app or the Lapua Club. If you contact us, please include your name, country, and email address as this helps us to ensure that we accept amendments only from the correct person. We encourage you to update your personal information as soon as it changes.
We will securely retain your information for as long as you are an active user of our service(s) where you have added your personal information and in accordance with applicable law. If you wish to submit a request that your data be deleted, please write to us at the above address. We will then delete your data within one (1) month after your request. You have the right to receive a copy of the personal information that we hold about you. Please write to us at the address above if you wish to exercise this right. If your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, we may charge a small fee towards the cost of administering any request you make or refuse to act on the request.
Rights of data subjects
As a data subject residing in the European Union, you have the right to access, rectify, cancel, and object to the processing of your personal data by directing any such requests to us. We allow you to exercise these rights by submitting a data subject request form to us and after we have verified your identity.
When processing of your personal data is based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You may easily withdraw your consent by contacting us at dpo.lapua(a)nammo.com or dpo.lapuaclub(a)nammo.com (if related to the Lapua Club profile).
Furthermore, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority.
6. Changes to this privacy policy
From time to time we may change this privacy policy. We recommend that you check this page periodically in order to review the latest version. We assume that all visitors of our website, registered users in the Lapua Ballistics App or Lapua Club, or our followers on social media platforms have carefully read this document and agree to its contents. If someone does not agree with this privacy policy, they should refrain from using our website and platforms. We reserve the right to change our privacy policy as necessity dictates. We will notify you of any substantial changes by sending an email or in another effective manner to give you a reasonable notice period to assess the consequences of such changes.
Continued use of our website www.lapua.com, our mobile app Lapua Ballistics, our service Lapua Club, or our brand or company pages on various social media platforms after having been informed of any such changes to these conditions implies acceptance of the revised privacy policy.
Lapua Data Subject Request Form(pdf)
About us
Production sites
Legal notice
Privacy Policy
Ammunition
All Calibers
Sport shooting ammunition
Hunting ammunition
Part of Nammo group
We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. If you continue to use this site we will assume that you are happy with it.Ok
